## **David Chipundo**

32 Flemming RD , Southerton, Harare, ZW, 00263 263-788-424929 | <a href="mailto:chipundodavid@gmail..com">chipundodavid@gmail..com</a> |

### **Profile**

Full stack web and mobile developer with a love of beating personal bests in IT and everything in its orbit. 8+ years of experience. Looking to leverage strong programming skills as a developer and expand into data science and AI. I am looking for a company willing to offer me a placement among their developers. In return, I would offer my full commitment, and be a pleasant and friendly addition to your team

## Personal Detail

Gender: Male D.O.B: 1991

Marital status: Single

## Skills

- Code and Deploy Web Applications in a Cross-Platform, Cross-Browser Environment
- Document Project Build and Maintenance
- Experience with Git, Mercurium and supporting online platform GitHub
- Experience development and consumption of REST-Based APIs
- Knowledgeable of Web Application Development Frameworks
- Proficient with some of the popular frontend web frameworks (Angular and PWAs)
- Proficient with C# MVC, .Net Core, Entity Framework , Web API, PHP Laravel , JavaScript,
   TypeScript )
- Solid Understanding of Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Strong Problem Solver
- Thrive in a Team Environment
- Troubleshoot and Communicate Effectively
- Experience with building mobile applications using Android studio and Ionic
- Familiar with some of cloud service (Microsoft Azure and Google Platform )
- Experience in front end development using BaaS (Firebase and Auth0)

## Experience

**Freelancing**Web Developer
2013 – 2015

- Writing well designed, testable, efficient code by using best software development practices
- Creating website layout/user interfaces by using standard HTML/CSS/ Bootstrap practices
- Integrate data from various back-end services and databases
- Gather and refine specifications and requirements based on technical needs
- Create and maintain software documentation
- Be responsible for maintaining, expanding, and scaling our site
- Stay plugged into emerging technologies/industry trends and apply them into operations and activities

361 ICT. Harare

Full-stack web + Android developer

Jan 2018 – Apr 2018

- Designing algorithms and flowcharts
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications
- Integrate software components and third-party programs
- Developing android mobile apps
- Verify and deploy programs and systems
- Troubleshoot, debug and upgrade existing software
- Recommend and execute improvements
- Create technical documentation for reference and reporting

WEBDEV. Harare

ANGULAR / PWA /. NETCORE developer

2018 - 2019

- Designing algorithms and flowcharts
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications
- Integrate software components and third-party programs
- Developing android .net apps and PWAs

PNR HOST. Harare

LARAVEL/PWA developer Mar 2019 – Aug 2019

- Voluntarily helping a not-yet-funded start-up company to develop its products
  - Planning team efficient and platform based solutions
  - Integrate software components and third-party programs

AT TELECOMMS. Harare

React/ ANGULAR/PWA developer

August 2019 – present

- Designing algorithms and flowcharts
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications
- Integrate software components and third-party programs

#### **Recent work:**

https://edgeonline.co.zw/ https://sip.nyaradzo.global/ https://www.mystoro.com/ https://www.autozoom.com/ https://www.topup.co.zw/ https://disciplesoft.co.za/

#### Apps:

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.disciplesoft.testings.discipleship&hl=en\_IE https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.churchapp.disciplesoft.bcc

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=zw.co.webdev.total

# Education

Masvingo
2007

### Masvingo Polytechnic

Masvingo

National Diploma in Information Technology

2013

# Online Acquired

Programming using C# Angular 2+	2012 2016
Laravel	2015
Android	2014
.Net Core	2017
GCP (firebase)	2016
AZURE	2015
PWA	2018
FLUTTER	2019

## Referee

Aaron Katema 361ict CTO ±263775391733

Waynne Mubata AT telecomms Lead Developer ±263783400135